

Front-end Web Developer

Languages: Mandarin

alexaaron.weber@gmail.com | +1 (248) 790 8803 | Pleasant Ridge, MI **LinkedIn** | **GitHub** | **Portfolio**

SUMMARY

I am a front-end web developer and creative with diverse experience in language, landscaping, design and an eye for detail. I have a degree in Asian Studies where I discovered my passion for learning new languages. After returning from two years of living in Wuhan, China as an English Teacher, I devoted myself to developing tech skills. I love having creative outlets and learning new technologies! So far in my studies of coding, I've created a few projects using Angular and Web APIs. This helped me develop familiarity with Agile practices, the command line, responsive design, and scalable functionality. I've also used my passion for languages to build my knowledge of programming languages. Because of my experience in landscaping, I would love to design stunning software to satisfy customers' aesthetic desires and preferences.

EDUCATION

Grand Circus Front-end Bootcamp, Detroit, Michigan

July 2020 – September 2020

Projects include: Scrum's Pets (Javascript) | Cinéma (Angular) | WellBeing (Angular)

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China

September 2019 - May 2020

Courses toward Masters in Enterprise Management

Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan

Bachelors in Asian Studies with a concentration in Chinese

August 2012 - May 2017

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS3
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- Angular

- PostareSQL
- Design Frameworks
- Web APIs
- UI/UX

- TDD
- Object Oriented Design
- Git/GitHub
- Scrum/Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

English Language Teacher

August 2018 – January 2020

Huazhong University of Science and Technology - Wuhan, China

- Outcomes: Over 150 students improved their confidence to speak publicly in English by role-playing every-day scenarios, open forum discussions of current events, and creative expression through skits and topical presentations.
- Responsibilities: Mentored students, in groups of 30+ and one-on-one, through lectures and activities centered around English to improve confidence and language capabilities.

Foreman (Seasonal)

February 2017 – Present

Down to Earth Lawn Service - Oak Park, Michigan

- Outcomes 150+ repeat customers continue to sign up every year for various landscape services throughout the Spring, Autumn, and Summer seasons.
- Responsibilities Guided lawn crews in servicing weekly maintenance to over 130 residential customers' lawns and
 dozens of commercial properties, as well as occasionally implementing other landscape designs tailored to customer
 desires.